## Alice Zhang

Education

2018-present Bachelor, University of British Columbia, Vancouver- Canada, Biomedical Engineering.

Experience

present Data Analyst, Centre for Heart Lung Innovation, Vancouver Canada.

I worked under Dr. Zachary Laksman to develop an assay to profile iPSCs(induced Pluripotent Stem Cells) and cardiomyocytes subjected to different chemical perturbations. The pipeline produced allows rapid and inexpensive profiling of iPSCs, and the extracted data sets can provide important information about their morphology. This internship allowed me to cultivate skills in data analysis, algorithm implementation, and data visualization. Applying software in a research setting has given me a better foundation in Python, R, and MySQL.

2018-present **Team member**, Supermileage design team, UBC.

For the past three years I have been a member of UBC Supermileage, an engineering student design team that designs and builds fuel efficient vehicles. This year I am part of a special 3D printing sub team with a focus on printing poly-carbonates. Being a part of this specialized team has allowed me to learn more about 3D printing, as well as develop my communication and interpersonal skills. I have become familiar with software such as Solid Works and Cura, and am confident building and operating a 3D printer.

2016–2017 **Hostess**, *Heirloom Fine Dining*, Vancouver Canada.

I was responsible for greeting and seating guests at the door, as well as organizing reservations and waiting times to ensure guest satisfaction. I communicated with all other employees to ensure smooth operation during busy hours. I developed strong communication skills during this job, and was able to work efficiently in a fast- paced environment.

Languages

English Native

Mandarin Intermediate

Knowledge Area

Backend Java, Python, C, R

Database MySQL, SSH, VM

Other Microsoft Office, SolidWorks, LATEX, MatLab, Fiji, CellProfiler

About me

I am currently a 3<sup>rd</sup> year biomedical engineering student at the University of British Columbia, with a specialization in bioinformatics. I have a strong interest in electrical and software systems, and would like to make an impact on the growing technology industry.